<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-GB"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-GB" /><updated>2019-01-10T15:50:21+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">VOiCES</title><subtitle>The Voices Obscured in Complex Environmental Settings (VOiCES) corpus is a creative commons speech dataset targeting acoustically challenging and reverberant environments with robust labels and truth data for transcription, denoising, and speaker identification.</subtitle><author><name>VishalSandesara# jekyll-seo-tag &gt; default author</name></author><entry><title type="html">VOiCES Appearing At Interspeech 2018</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/general/2018/09/01/interspeech-2018/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="VOiCES Appearing At Interspeech 2018" /><published>2018-09-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-09-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/general/2018/09/01/interspeech-2018</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/general/2018/09/01/interspeech-2018/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&quot;right&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;/images/interspeech-logo.png&quot; /&gt;
Lab41 and SRI International will be attending &lt;a href=&quot;http://interspeech2018.org/&quot;&gt;Interspeech&lt;/a&gt; 2018, to be hosted in Hyderabad, India September 2-6. We will be presenting details of the corpus as well as outlining results from model baselines when using VOiCES. Come visit our poster.
Conference publication available &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.isca-speech.org/archive/Interspeech_2018/pdfs/1454.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;:
Recent advances in speech and signal processing research leverage deep learning frameworks that can model data complexity better than more traditional approaches. Publicly available audio corpora that are large enough for deep learning implementations are mostly composed of isolated speech at close range microphony. A typical approach to better represent realistic scenarios, is to convolve clean speech with noise and simulated room response for model training. Despite these efforts model performance significantly degrades when tested against un-curated data collected in the wild. This paper introduces the Voices Obscured In Complex Environmental Settings (VOICES) corpus, a freely available dataset under Creative Commons BY 4.0. This dataset will promote speech and signal processing research under noisy room conditions for speakers at a distance. Data was recorded in furnished rooms with distractor noise played in conjunction with isolated speech. Multiple sessions were recorded in each room to accommodate for all foreground speech-distractor noise combinations. Audio was recorded using twelve microphones placed throughout the room, resulting in 120 hours of recordings per microphone. This work is a multi-organizational effort led by SRI International and Lab41 with the intent to push forward state of the art distant microphone approaches in signal processing and speech recognition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&quot;left&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; src=&quot;/images/Interspeech2018-poster-v2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://interspeech2018.org/&quot;&gt;Interspeech 2018&lt;/a&gt; was held September 2-6, 2018 in Hyderabad, India.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>VishalSandesara# jekyll-seo-tag &gt; default author</name></author><category term="General" /><summary type="html">Lab41 and SRI International will be presenting at the Interspeech annual meeting in September 2-6, 2018. We will be available for questions at our poster session.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://picsum.photos/2560/600?image=733" /></entry><entry><title type="html">VOiCES Appearing At ASA 2018</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/general/2018/05/07/asa-2018/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="VOiCES Appearing At ASA 2018" /><published>2018-05-07T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/general/2018/05/07/asa-2018</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/general/2018/05/07/asa-2018/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&quot;right&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;http://acousticalsociety.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/ASA_Web_logo.png&quot; /&gt;
Lab41 and SRI International will be attending the &lt;a href=&quot;http://acousticalsociety.org/&quot;&gt;Acoustical Society of America&lt;/a&gt; at 2018, May 7-11. We will be presenting our work in presentation. Details about our corpus will be provided. We will also be handing out VOiCES flyers and talking with prospectives as well as promoting the corpus. Come visit our poster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;: 
Voices Obscured in Complex Environmental Setting (VOiCES) corpus is a collaboration between Lab41 and SRI International, designed to be a freely available data set for speech and acoustics research in noisy room conditions.  The main focus of the corpus is on distant microphone collection in a series of four rooms of different sizes and configurations. There are both foreground speech and background adversarial sounds, played through high-quality speakers in each room to create multiple, realistic acoustic environments. The foreground speech is played from a randomly rotating speaker to emulate head motion.  Foreground speech consists of approximately 15 hours of audio from LibriVox audio collections per session per microphone and the background distractor sounds will consist of babble, music, HVAC, TV/radio, dogs, vehicles and weather sounds drawn from the MUSAN collection. Each room has multiple sessions to exhaustively cover the background foreground combinations, and the audio is collected with twelve different microphones (omnidirectional lavalier, studio cardioid and piezoelectric) placed strategically around the room. The resulting data set was designed to enable acoustic research on event detection, background detection, source separation, speech enhancement, source distance, sound localization, as well as speech research on speaker recognition, speech activity detection, speech recognition and language recognition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&quot;left&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; src=&quot;/images/voices_ASA_poster.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://acousticalsociety.org/&quot;&gt;Acoustical Society of America Meeting&lt;/a&gt; was held from May 7-11, 2018 in Minneapolis, Minnesota.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>VishalSandesara# jekyll-seo-tag &gt; default author</name></author><category term="General" /><summary type="html">Lab41 and SRI International will be presenting at the Acoustical Society of America's annual meeting in May 7-11, 2018. We will be available for questions at our poster session.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://picsum.photos/2560/600?image=733" /></entry><entry><title type="html">VOiCES Appearing At ICASSP 2018</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/general/2018/04/15/icassp-2018/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="VOiCES Appearing At ICASSP 2018" /><published>2018-04-15T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-04-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/general/2018/04/15/icassp-2018</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/general/2018/04/15/icassp-2018/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&quot;right&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;/images/icassp_2018.png&quot; /&gt;
Lab41 and SRI International will be attending the &lt;a href=&quot;https://2018.ieeeicassp.org/default.asp&quot;&gt;International Conference of Acoustics Speech and Signal Processing&lt;/a&gt; at 2018, April 15. We will be handing out VOiCES flyers and talking with prospectives as well as promoting the corpus. Come visit us at the booths!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://2018.ieeeicassp.org/default.asp&quot;&gt;IEEE ICASSP 2018 conference&lt;/a&gt; will be held from April 15-20, 2018 in Calgary, Canada. This year, their theme is “Signal Processing and Artificial Intelligence: Changing the World”.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>VishalSandesara# jekyll-seo-tag &gt; default author</name></author><category term="General" /><summary type="html">Lab41 and SRI International will be attending the International Conference of Acoustics Speech and Signal Processing at 2018. We will be handing out VOiCES flyers and talking with prospectives as well as promoting the corpus. Come visit us at the booths!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://picsum.photos/2560/600?image=733" /></entry></feed>